Everybody has a soul. Joe Gardner is about to find his.
Soul is a animation, family, comedy film directed by Pete Docter.
Joe Gardner is a middle school teacher with a love for jazz music.
After a successful audition at the Half Note Club, he suddenly gets into an accident that separates his soul from his body and is
transported to the You Seminar, a center in which souls develop and gain passions before being transported to a newborn child.
Joe must enlist help from the other souls-in-training, like 22, a soul who has
spent eons in the You Seminar, in order to get back to Earth.
Joe Gardner (voice), played by Jamie Foxx.
22 (voice), played by Tina Fey.
Moonwind (voice), played by Graham Norton.
Terry (voice), played by Rachel House.
Counselor Jerry (voice), played by Alice Braga.
Counselor Jerry (voice), played by Richard Ayoade.
Soul is a 2020 American animated fantasy comedy-drama film produced
by Pixar Animation Studios for Walt Disney Pictures.
Directed by Pete Docter, who co-wrote it with Mike Jones and Kemp Powers, the film stars the voices of Jamie Foxx, Tina Fey, Graham
Norton, Rachel House, Alice Braga, Richard Ayoade, Phylicia Rashad, Donnell Rawlings, Questlove, and Angela Bassett.
It follows Joe Gardner (Foxx), a middle school teacher and aspiring pianist who falls into a coma following an
accident and seeks to reunite his separated soul and body in time for his big break as a jazz musician.
Docter conceived Soul in January 2016, examining the origins of
human personalities and the concept of determinism.
During his first meeting with Jones, he pitched the idea about
spacetime involving souls with personalities.
The film's producers consulted various jazz musicians, including Herbie Hancock and Terri Lyne Carrington,
and animated its musical sequences using the sessions of musician Jon Batiste as a reference.
Apart from Batiste's original jazz compositions, musicians Trent
Reznor and Atticus Ross composed the film's score.
Production on Soul lasted for four years on an approximate $150 million budget.
It was the first Pixar film to feature a black lead.
Soul premiered at the BFI London Film Festival on October 11, 2020, and was scheduled for theatrical
release on June 19 and November 20; however, it was postponed due to the COVID-19 pandemic.
It was released direct-to-streaming on Disney+ on December 25, 2020, accompanied by the
short film Burrow, and in theaters in countries without the streaming service.
It was theatrically released in the United States on January 12, 2024,
and grossed over $122 million at the worldwide box office.
The National Board of Review and the American Film Institute
named Soul one of the top ten films of 2020.
It was nominated for three Academy Awards at the 93rd Academy Awards,
winning two, and received numerous other accolades.
The film explores themes of new york city, jazz, musician, cat, self-discovery.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.